Hungry for Adventure...Burning to Fight!
Johnny Tremain is a drama, family, war film directed by Robert Stevenson.
When an injury bars him from pursuing his trade, Revolutionary War-era silversmith's apprentice Johnny Tremain finds a new life
in the ranks of the Sons of Liberty army, taking part in the Boston Tea Party and Paul Revere's legendary ride.
Johnny Tremain, played by Hal Stalmaster.
Rab Silsbee, played by Richard Beymer.
Cilla Lapham, played by Luana Patten.
James Otis, played by Jeff York.
Jonathan Lyte, played by Sebastian Cabot.
Samuel Adams, played by Rusty Lane.
Johnny Tremain is a work of historical fiction written in 1943 by Esther Forbes that is
set in Boston prior to and during the outbreak of the American Revolution.
Intended for teen-aged readers, the novel's themes include apprenticeship, courtship, sacrifice,
human rights, and the growing tension between Patriots and Loyalists as conflict nears.
Events depicted in the novel include the Boston Tea Party, the British blockade of the Port of
Boston, the midnight ride of Paul Revere, and the Battles of Lexington and Concord.
The book won the 1944 Newbery Medal and was believed to be "among the 20 best-selling children's books of the 20th century." It was estimated
to be the 16th-bestselling children's paperback book as of the year 2001 in the United States, according to Publishers Weekly.
In 1957, Walt Disney Pictures released a film
adaptation, also called Johnny Tremain.
The film explores themes of patriot, merchant, sons of liberity.
The tone is emotional.